Bad data visualizations can be summed up as visuals that don't convey your message well.
يمكن تلخيص عرض البيانات السيئ باعتباره عناصر مرئية لا تنقل رسالتكم بشكل جيد.
If a visualization is misleading or hides and distracts your message,
إذا كانت المرئيات مضللة أو تخفي رسالتك أو تصرف الانتباه عنها،
you need to consider changes to your visualization.
فعليكم التفكير في إجراء بعض التغييرات على هذه المرئيات.
Let's look at some misleading examples.
لنلقِ نظرة على بعض الأمثلة المضللة.
This is a popular image for showing bad visualizations.
هذه صورة شائعة لعرض مرئيات سيئة.
Here, you can see that this plot is misleading by making
يمكنكم أن تروا هنا أن هذا المخطط مضلل جدًا عن طريق إجراء
a small difference seem much larger than it actually is by zooming in on the difference.
اختلاف بسيط يبدو أكبر بكثير مما هو عليه في الواقع عن طريق تكبير منطقة الاختلاف.
This is a poor visualization due to the fact that it's misleading.
هذه مرئيات سيئة لأنها مضللة.
A second example was made popular by Cole,
مثال ثانٍ لقى شعبية كبيرة من كتاب كول،
who we mentioned in an earlier concept.
والذي ذكرناه في مفهوم سابق.
Consider these two pie charts for understanding how
اطلعوا على هذين المخططين الدائريين لفهم كيفية
a summer science camp for kids impacts their interests on learning about science.
تأثير معسكر علوم صيفي للأطفال في اهتماماتهم بدراسة العلوم.
Can you tell if the camp was effective in raising the interest rates in science?
هل يمكنكم أن تخبروني بما إذا كان هذا المعسكر فعالًا في رفع معدلات الاهتمام بدراسة العلوم أم لا؟
This is an example of a visual that hides or distracts from the message.
هذا مثال عن العناصر المرئية التي تخفي الرسالة أو تصرف الانتباه عنها.
Comparing the areas of the pie charts and
مقارنة مناطق المخططات الدائرية
all the colors make it difficult to see the message.
وجميع الألوان تجعل رؤية الرسالة أمرًا صعبًا.
Another plot from Cole's book is this pie chart.
ومثال آخر من كتاب كول وهو هذا المخطط الدائري.
You might guess that this piece of the pie is the largest in terms of the suppliers.
قد تعتقدون أن هذا الجزء من المخطط الدائري هو الجزء الأكبر لعدد الموردين.
You would be wrong,
ستخطئون،
it's actually this piece.
إنه حقًا هذا الجزء.
The 3D aspect of the chart is misleading.
إن الجانب ثلاثي الأبعاد من المخطط مضلل.
And, again, humans are not great at identifying differences based on these areas.
ومرة أخرى، لا يكون الأشخاص متميزين في تحديد الاختلافات حسب هذه المناطق.
Here is an example of a race track chart.
إليكم مثال عن مخطط لمضمار السباق.
Though one bar is clearly longer than the other,
على الرغم من أن أحد الأشرطة يبدو أطول من الآخر بوضوح،
they represent the same percentage.
إلا أنهما يعرضان النسبة المئوية نفسها.
This makes for some confusion.
قد يؤدي ذلك إلى بعض الارتباك.
Additionally, the bright red here suggests that this group is more important.
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، يشير اللون الاحمر الناصع إلى أن هذه المجموعة أكثر أهمية.
If this isn't the case,
وإذا لم يكن الأمر كذلك،
then this coloring seems misleading.
فإن الألوان تبدو مضللة.
With just two bars,
مع وجود شريطين فقط،
we might not even need a chart but rather just a statement of the message.
قد لا نحتاج إلى مخطط حتى، بل لمجرد بيان للرسالة.
Visualizations become more useful as
تصبح المرئيات أكثر فائدة
the amount of information we need to convey increases.
كلما ازداد حجم المعلومات التي نحتاجها لنقلها.
At the same time,
في الوقت نفسه،
adding extra elements to the visuals that do
يجب تجنب إضافة عناصر إضافية إلى العناصر المرئية التي
not convey the message in your data should be avoided.
لا تنقل الرسالة في بياناتكم.
I urge you to strive for elegance and simplicity in your visuals.
أحثكم على الالتزام بالأناقة والبساطة في العناصر المرئية.
Here, you saw some examples of poor visuals.
رأيت هنا بعض الأمثلة عن العناصر المرئية السيئة.
You might have some ideas of how to improve these already.
قد يكون لديكم بعض الأفكار عن كيفية تحسين هذه الأمثلة بالفعل.
We will look at some improved visuals in the upcoming concepts.
سنطلع على بعض الصور المحسنة في المفاهيم القادمة.